Now, we're trying to build an artificial
现在我们来创建人工智能
intelligence that can solve problems like this all on it's own.
让其独立地为这类问题求解
You can see that the search algorithms do a great job of finding
你可以看到搜索算法很擅长
solutions to problems like this.
寻找这类问题的解
But you might complain that in order for the search algorithms to work,
但你可能会抱怨 为了让搜索算法生效
we had to provide it with a heuristic function.
我们得为算法提供启发式函数
The heuristic function came from the outside.
而启发式函数是来自外界的
You might think that coming up with a good heuristic function is really where
你可能会想 这所谓的智能
all the intelligence is.
不外乎是沾了好的启发式函数的光
And so, a problem solver that uses a heuristic function given to it really
因此 借助了给定启发式函数的问题求解程序
isn't intelligent at all.
根本不能称为智能
So let's think about where the intelligence could come from, and
那我们来想想智能可以源自哪里
can we automatically come up with good heuristic functions.
想想我们能否自动生成优秀的启发式函数
I'm going to sketch a description of a program that can automatically come up
我要大致描述下这么个程序
with good heuristics given a description of a problem.
它能根据问题描述来自动生成优秀的启发式函数
Now suppose this program is given a description of
假设程序得到的问题描述是
the sliding blocks puzzle where we say that a block can move
滑块类推盘游戏 游戏中
from square A to square B if A is adjacent to B and B is blank.
如果 A 和 B 相邻 且 B 是空格 那么滑块就可以从 A 移动到 B
Now imagine that we try to loosen this restriction, we cross out B is blank and
现在假设我们要放松这一限制 把 B 是空格这一条去掉
then we get the rule a block can move from A to B if A is adjacent to B.
那规则就变成了 如果 A 与 B 相邻 那滑块就可以从 A 移动到 B
And that's equal to our heuristic h2 because a block can
这就和启发式函数 h2 一样了 因为滑块
move anywhere to an adjacent state.
可以移动到任意相邻位置上
Now we could also cross out the other part of the rule, and
现在我们把另一部分规则也去掉
we now get a block can move from any square A to any square B
所以规则变成了滑块可以从任意 A 位置移动到任意 B 位置
regardless of any condition, and that gives us heuristic h1.
没有任何条件限制 这就得到了启发式函数 h1
So we see that both of our heuristics can be derived from
因此我们发现 两个启发式函数都可以通过
a simple mechanical manipulation of the formal description of the problem.
对问题形式化描述进行简单机械调整来推导出来
Once we've generated automatically these candidate heuristics,
等我们自动生成了这两个候选的启发式函数
another way to come up with a good heuristic is to say that a new
就可以用另一个办法来生成优秀的启发式函数了
heuristic h is equal to the maximum of h1 and h2.
即新启发式函数 h 等于 (h1, h2) 的最大值
And that's guaranteed to be admissible as long as h1 and h2 are admissible,
只要 h1 和 h2 可采纳 h 就一定是可采纳的
because it still never overestimates,
因为它也永远不会高估
and guaranteed to be better because it's getting closer to the true value.
而且因为更接近真实数值 所以能保证效果更好
The only problem with combining multiple heuristics like this is that
像这样结合多个启发式函数 唯一的问题就在于
there is some cost to compute the heuristic, and
计算启发式函数会有所消耗
it could take longer to compute even if we end up expanding fewer paths.
就算我们得以拓展更少路径 计算所耗费的时间也可能更长
Now crossing out parts of the rules like this is called generating a relaxed
像这样去除部分规则的操作叫做生成松弛问题
problem, what we've done is we've taken the original problem where it's hard to
我们所做的就是取原始问题 这个时候滑块很难移动
move squares around and made it easier by relaxing one of the constrains.
然后放宽一些限制 从而简化该问题
And you can see that as adding new links in the state's space.
往状态中添加新连接也体现了这一点
So if we have a state space in which there are only particular links,
假设状态空间原本只有几个连接
by relaxing the problem it's as if we're adding
而放宽问题限制 就相当于我们
new operators that traverse the state in new ways.
添加了新的算子 能以新方式在状态空间中移动
And so adding new operators only makes the problem easier.
所以添加新算子只会简化问题
And thus never over estimates and thus is admissible.
而永远不会高估问题 因此是可采纳的